<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dht on gpestana</title>
    <link>https://gpestana.com/tags/dht/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dht on gpestana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gpestana.com/tags/dht/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coin Flipping Request Delegation</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/coin-flipping-request-delegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/coin-flipping-request-delegation/</guid>
      <description>The goal of Coin Flipping Request Delegation (CFRD) is to add plausible deniability of routing and lookup requests in P2P networks, with special emphasis on DHT networks. The CFRD lookup protocol works by probabilistically creating a new lookup from a received routing request.
CFRD in Kademlia DHT In a Kademlia lookup request (as defined by these specs), the lookup initiator creates an ordered shortlist containing k peers closest to the ID of the contentID requested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2P privacy vulnerabilities - the DHT case</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/p2p-privacy-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/p2p-privacy-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>DHT lookups are extremely vulnerable to attacks on the lookup mechanism (both active and passive)
(castro et al)
 castro et al buddy mechanism onion routing lnd  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Pursuit of Private DHTs</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/in-pursuit-of-private-dhts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/in-pursuit-of-private-dhts/</guid>
      <description>Services based on P2P and decentralized networks are reaching mass adoption (e.g. Bitcoin, Ethereum, IPFS, Dat). People are calling this new wave of distributed and decentralized systems the Web 3.0. Many of these services and networks rely heavily on Distributed Hash Tables (DHTs) - e.g. IPFS, bittorrent - or use it as an important building block (e.g. Ethereum). It is expected that DHTs will be an important building block for many networks and services for the Web 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>