<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on gpestana</title>
    <link>https://gpestana.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on gpestana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gpestana.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/capital/</guid>
      <description>I cherish the moments when I come across people who are well spoken and can get their mental model of the world across with clarity. These people often push me to think deeply about their views of the world. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a podcast episode hosted by Russel Brand, where Yanis Varoufakis was the guest. They discussed about the state of Europe, the times of Varoufakis as Greek finance minister, the degeneration of capitalism and its institutions, how commodification and alienation of our society and values are turning us into miserable people, detached from humanity and raw material for keeping the current system of capital accumulation by the few alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Pursuit of Private DHTs</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/in-pursuit-of-private-dhts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/in-pursuit-of-private-dhts/</guid>
      <description>Services based on P2P and decentralized networks are reaching mass adoption (e.g. Bitcoin, Ethereum, IPFS, Dat). People are calling this new wave of distributed and decentralized systems the Web 3.0. Many of these services and networks rely heavily on Distributed Hash Tables (DHTs) - e.g. IPFS, bittorrent - or use it as an important building block (e.g. Ethereum). It is expected that DHTs will be an important building block for many networks and services for the Web 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on AWS ECS configuration and secret management done right</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/aws-conf-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/aws-conf-management/</guid>
      <description>Best practices for managing secrets and configurations in ECS containers:
Requirements:  configurations and secrets stored in paramter store and/or S3 bucket; encrypt secrets; do not push configurations to git/version control system; transparent to apps (e.g. it should be completely transparent for backend; it should not have code for pulling configurations/secrets from anywhere) this follows the 12 factor app style (https://12factor.net/); automatic reloads new configurations when these change upstream;  envaws (https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why everyone should be using Tor</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/why-use-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/why-use-tor/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been interesting weeks for those who have been thinking about online privacy and data protection and what does it mean in today&amp;rsquo;s hyper connected society. Although this is a multi layered problem - personal data can be collected at different network layers and in multiple ways- one of the most effective ways to protect our personal data is to use the Tor network.
When I tell friends and non so technical people that they should be accessing the web through technologies that are used to access the dark web, I&amp;rsquo;m often received surprised reactions, fear, confusion and even disgust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Store the data the smart way</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/store-data-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/store-data-smart/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; This post is part of the series &amp;ldquo;The Zen of Data Pipelines&amp;rdquo; which explores how to build scalable and robust data systems. Most of the ideas and best practices described in this series were learned while implementing and maintaining a large scale data pipeline at F-Secure for the Rapid Detection Service. You can find more posts of this series in this blog or all series content in Gitbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t trust the data</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/dont-trust-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/dont-trust-the-data/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; This post is part of the series &amp;ldquo;The Zen of Data Pipelines&amp;rdquo; which explores how to build scalable and robust data systems. Most of the ideas and best practices described in this series were learned while implementing and maintaining a large scale data pipeline at F-Secure for the Rapid Detection Service. You can find more posts of this series in this blog or all series content in Gitbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the moral imperative to leave social networks</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/leaving-social-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/leaving-social-networks/</guid>
      <description>there is a moral imperative to leave the main social networks if they continue to operate as they do. while connecting people is a noble thing, exploiting them for money is unethical to say the least.
the dopamine shots carefully engineered to hook us up are ethically and morally wrong. those strategies do not improve user&amp;rsquo;s well being or satisfaction with the product. users come back because they become addicted to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why have one pipeline when you can have multiple?</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/multiple-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/multiple-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; This post is part of the series &amp;ldquo;The Zen of Data Pipelines&amp;rdquo; which explores how to build scalable and robust data systems. Most of the ideas and best practices described in this series were learned while implementing and maintaining a large scale data pipeline at F-Secure for the Rapid Detection Service. You can find more posts of this series in this blog or all series content in Gitbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do microservices (and avoid nanoservices)</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/data-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/data-microservices/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt; This post is part of the series &amp;ldquo;The Zen of Data Pipelines&amp;rdquo; which explores how to build scalable and robust data systems. Most of the ideas and best practices described in this series were learned while implementing and maintaining a large scale data pipeline at F-Secure for the Rapid Detection Service. You can find more posts of this series in this blog or all series content in Gitbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing credentials in production</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/managing-production-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/managing-production-credentials/</guid>
      <description>Every software must deal and manage credentials at some point. I will define credentials in the context of this article as secrets that must be protected at all costs, under risk of seriously compromising the security of production systems. There are several points to have in mind when managing credentials of productions systems:
Credentials storage should be kept secret by encryption and a strong access management. Credentials must never be transported but stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kapacitor-unit: unit tests framework for TICKscripts</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/kapacitor-unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/kapacitor-unit/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses ideas for a proof of concept for a unit test framework for Kapacitor&amp;rsquo;s TICKscripts and alerts. If you are not familiar with Kapacitor and the TICK script I really suggest you to go ahead and check InfluxData&amp;rsquo;s website and learn more about it! In short, the TICK stack is a time series data platform that allows you to easily store, analyse and act on time series data at scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus manager for JS</title>
      <link>https://gpestana.com/blog/consensus-manager-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gpestana.com/blog/consensus-manager-js/</guid>
      <description>In one of my side-project - which uses socket.io - I need to reach a consensus amongst users in the same room. Initial requirements:
 The definition of &amp;lsquo;consensus&amp;rsquo; should be flexible and interchangeable in run-time; The time to reach the consensus should be tracked; The final consensus amongst the clients could possibly output some data that the server may need to use further on;  My solution consists of a modular entity which I pompously called consensus manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>